<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Filip Tomasz Wieland</title>
    <description>Software developer and web enthusiast. Gap year between college and university. Currently works for chaser.io</description>
    <link>http://www.filipwieland.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.filipwieland.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2014 21:50:41 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2014 21:50:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>UCAS as an Individual, Part One</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I do not believe I am wrong in saying that the majority of university applicants go
through &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UCAS&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;UCAS&lt;/a&gt; as part of their
sixth form experience. In fact, I did the same thing back with
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ctksfc.ac.uk/site/aquinas/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Christ the King: Aquinas&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;references-and-statements&quot;&gt;References and statements&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found writing my personal statement to be relatively straightforward compared
to obtaining a reference from one of my previous teachers. Your general options
for getting people to look at your statement are to either bother your friends
or try and crowdsource it by involving, say, the entire
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.the-enlightened.info/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;London Enlightened&lt;/a&gt;
community (Enlightened of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ingress_(game)&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ingress&lt;/a&gt; variety).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing to note when writing your personal statement is that the 4000 character
limit is not &lt;em&gt;exactly&lt;/em&gt; the source of truth - it has to be something along the
lines of 4000 characters across 47 lines under their line-breaking algorithm,
oh and if you use a new-line character it will count as two because of the
&lt;code&gt;\r\n&lt;/code&gt; convention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So while the UCAS Apply, uh, application is a whole failboat’s worth of WTF in and of
itself (more on that in a future blog post), I think one of the most difficult
parts of the process is getting a reference. Unlike a regular character or personal
reference, this one should underline the applicant’s learning ability and passion
for the subject they chose. It is not trying to convince an HR person to
hire somebody, but rather an admissions tutor to offer somebody a place at
university. Therefore, I believe that good quality references of such type are more
likely to come from one’s teachers rather than an employer or colleague.
Obtaining such a reference whilst &lt;em&gt;at&lt;/em&gt; college is hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting one when you’ve already &lt;em&gt;left&lt;/em&gt; the college is much, much harder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pick-your-referee&quot;&gt;Pick your referee.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This should be someone who remembers you a lot, and that you trust to
write a solid, high-quality reference. Unfortunately, those teachers are usually
swamped by other students’ requests for references and help with personal
statements, which they have to prioritise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;prepare-to-email-them-a-lot&quot;&gt;Prepare to email them. A lot.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the oft-repeated phrase at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chaser.io&quot;&gt;Chaser&lt;/a&gt; is “polite persistence pays”.
While I can’t easily use this product for my current need (I’m chasing a reference,
not an overdue invoice), the principle itself is solid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am now sending up to 4 emails per week, to multiple members of staff in the
college. Some of them are general purpose reception emails which means I get to
perform miniature ‘amplification attacks’. As of me writing this, it is still
not enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;have-backups&quot;&gt;Have backups.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sincerely hope I’ve managed to get enough people to remember me in case I need
to ask someone else for a reference at the last minute. I hope to send off
my application by the end of November. If I can’t get the reference from my
primary person of choice by then, I’ll have to ask someone else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Half of the month has already gone past. Tick tock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Next in the series: In which I explain why your 4000-character statement is actually 4007 characters long&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.filipwieland.com/learning/2014/11/16/ucas-as-individual/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.filipwieland.com/learning/2014/11/16/ucas-as-individual/</guid>
        
        
        <category>learning</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Beginning</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been genuinely trying to come up with a reason why I might want to start
publishing a blog. Indeed, it may seem unnecessary. So why do I bother?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some aspects to it. First, this setup allows me to basically have any
content I like, including custom scripts, styles, and so on. It does not
limit me to the extent a third-party platform would. I have previously used
Blogger, and trying to do anything but the most basic text posts is nigh impossible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, as an effort to organise my writing into one coherent set. I have some
loose documents laying around that I’d like to tie together. Changelogs for my
projects. Short stories I never finished. Media critiques. That sort of stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And third, to create an archive of the weird and interesting stuff I come
across as a developer. In a way, being a ‘full(ish)-stack’ web developer
at the age of 18 is still kind of rare. This is very much an exciting
adventure for me, and I hope to document it here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will be adding more to the blog as I go along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;site-tech&quot;&gt;Site tech&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m currently using Jekyll to generate static HTML pages hosted on GitHub. I have a
Grunt task which wrangles Sass, Jekyll, and some basic JavaScript tasks to aid
development (but GitHub should pick up on everything anyway).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Header images are generated using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/btmills/geopattern&quot;&gt;geopattern&lt;/a&gt;
package based on the page title. I’ve written some JS to fade in the header as you
scroll down on blog pages. You can see it all in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/FLamparski/FLamparski.github.io&quot;&gt;the repo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.filipwieland.com/misc/2014/11/07/the-beginning/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.filipwieland.com/misc/2014/11/07/the-beginning/</guid>
        
        
        <category>misc</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
